Guide to the Exhibitions Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- PHILADELPHIA CENTENNIAL EXHIBITION, 1876, 1872-1878; Series I; 3.25 linear feet (8 boxes)
  - Bound Volumes. [Note: the number indicated in the Folder column is the number of the Volume]
    - Adams, James O. Centennial Papers. One Hundred Years' Rural Progress, and Reports and Addresses Relative to the Centennial Exhibition, 1876. (Concord: Edward A. Jenks), 1877 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Catalogue of Specimens of the Mineral and Agricultural Products from the Line of the Philadelphia and Reading Railroad, of Rails, &c. Manufactured at the Philadelphia and Reading Railroad Rolling-Mill, and of Models of Bridges in Use on the Line, Exhibited at the U.S. Centennial Exhibition, Philadelphia, 1876. (Philadelphia: Allen, Lane & Scott) (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Centennial Exposition. Catalogue of the Educational Exhibit of the State of Pennsylvania, With an Appendix, Containing an Outline of the System of Public Instruction in the State. (Lancaster: The Inquirer P. & P. Co.), 1876 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Centennial Exposition. Education and Science. Catalogue of the Exhibit in this Department from the State of Illinois. (Philadelphia), 1876 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Department of War, Corps of Engineers. Outline of Operations for the Removal of the Reef at Hallett's Point, Hell Gate New York, and Description of Steam Drilling Scow. Brevet Major-General John Newton, in Charge. Models Exhibited at the International Exhibition, 1876, Philadelphia., [ca. 1876] (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - International Exhibition, 1876. Department of Education and Science. (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Catalogue of the New Jersey Exhibit, South Gallery, Main Building. (Trenton: Nair, Day & Naar), 1876 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Catalogue of the Ohio Educational Exhibit. (Philadelphia: Franklin Printing House), 1876 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Journal of the Proceedings of the United States Centennial Commission at Philadelphia. Seventh Session., 1876 April (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Kansas at the Centennial. Report of the Centennial Managers to the Legislature of the State of Kansas. Embracing a History of Other International Exhibitions, Statements of Admissions and Receipts of Each, U.S. Centennial Commission, System of Awards, Classification, the Board of Finance, Description of Centennial Grounds, Including Buildings, Out-Door. Works of Art, Comforts and Accomodations, the Press, U.S. Government Exhibits, Foreign Commissions, Opening Day, Fourth of July, Closing Ceremonies, State Buildings, Kansas Before, at, and After the Centennial, etc., etc. Illustrated. (Topeka: Geo. W. Martin, Kansas Publishing House), 1877 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Killebrew, J.B. Tennessee: Its Agricultural & Mineral Wealth, With an Appendix, Showing the Extent, Value and Accessibility of Its Ores, With Analyses of the Same. (Nashville: Tavel, Eastman & Howell), 1876 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Maury, M.F. Catalogue of the West Virginia State Exhibit, at the International Exhibition at Philadelphia in 1876. Printed for the West Virginia Commission. (Philadelphia) (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Norrman, V. A Military Bridge-Equipage. (Philadelphia: J.B. Lippincott & Co.), 1876 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Nourse, C.C. Iowa and the Centennial. The State Address, Delivered. at Philadelphia, Thursday, September, 7, 1876. (Des Moines: Iowa State Register Print) (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Otis, George A. Check List of Preparations and Objects in the Section of Human Anatomy of the United States Medical Museum for Use During the International Exhibition of 1876 in Connection With the Representation of the Medical Department U.S. Army. No. 8. (Washington, D.C.: Army Medical Museum) (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - The Pacific Guano Company: Its History; Its Products and Trade; Its Relation to Agriculture. (Cambridge: The Riverside Press), 1876 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Report of the Massachusetts State Commissioner to the Centennial Exhibition at Philadelphia. 1876. (Boston:. Albert J. Wright), 1877 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Report of the New Jersey Commissioners on the Centennial Exhibition. (Trenton: Naar, Day & Naar), 1877 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Reports of Foreign Societies on Awarding Medals to the American Arctic Explorers, Kane, Hayes, Hall. (U.S. Naval Observatory), 1876 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - The State of Wisconsin, Embracing Brief Sketches of Its History, Position, Resources and Industries, and a Catalogue of Its Exhibits at. the Centennial at Philadelphia. 1876. (Madison: Atwood & Culver) (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - United States Centennial. Commission. International Exhibition. 1876. Special Catalogue of the Display of Poultry. October 27 to November 9, 1876. (Philadelphia: Sherman &Co.) (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Walker, David. Address on the History and Resources of the State, by Appointment of Governor Garland, at Judges' Hall, Centennial Grounds, Philadelphia, October 16, 1876. (Philadelphia: Collins, Printer) (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Philadelphia. Centennial exhibition, 1876. Women's Centennial committees. The national cookery book, comp. from original receipts, for the Women's centennial committees of the International exhibtion of 1876... Philadelphia, Women's centennial executive committee [c1876]. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - For additional literature on the Philadelphia Centennial Exhibition, 1876 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    See also: box 15, folders 34-36
    See also:box 16, folders 37-40
    See also: box 17, folder 49
- OTHER EXHIBITIONS, 1873-1933; Series II
  This series is made up of publications received after the original collection of publications from the Philadelphia Centennial Exhibition, 1876 had been arranged. Included is additional material from the Philadelphia Centennial Exhibition as well as publications from other world exhibitions. The material is arranged by accession.
  - Chicago. World's Columbian Exposition, 1893
    - Beautiful Scenes of the White City. A Portfolio of Original Copper-Plate Half-Tones of the World's Fair. Art Portfolio Series. Vol. I, No. 1, Part I. (Chicago: Laird & Lee), 1894 February 12 (Box 9)
  - Paris. Exposition universelle, 1867
    - Paris Universal Exhibition. The Complete Official Catalogue (English Version) Published Under the Authority of the Imperial Commission (London: J.M. Johnson & Sons), [1867] (Box 9)
  - Vienna. Weltausstellung, 1873
    - Vienna Universal Exhibition, 1873. Official Catalogue of the American Department. Edited by Eben Brewer, for the United States Commission. (London: J.M. Johnson & Sons) (Box 9)
    - Exner, Wilhelm Franz. Beiträge zur Geschichte der Gewerbe und Erfindungen Oesterreichs von der Mitte des XVIII, Jahrhunderts bis zur Gegenwart. Erste Reihe: Rohproduction und Industrie. (Wien: Wilhelm Braumüller), 1873 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Exner, Wilhelm Franz. Beiträge zur Geschichte der Gewerbe and Erfindungen Oesterreichs von der Mitte des XVIII, Jahrhunderts bis zur Gegenwart. Zweite Reihe: Ingenieur-Wissen, Wissenschftliche and Musikalische Instrumente, Unterricht. (Wien: Wilhelm Braumüller), 1873 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Gintl, Wilhelm Friedrich. Officieller Ausstellungs-Bericht Herausgegeben durch die General-Direction der Weltausstellung 1873. Die Zündwaaren und Explosivstoffe. (Gruppe III, Section 5.) (Wien: K.K. Hof- and Staatsdruckerei) (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Kupelwieser, Franz. Officieller Ausstellungs-Bericht Herausgegeben durch die General-Direction der Weltausstellung 1873. Das Hüttenwes en. (Gruppe I, Section 2 und 3.) (Wien: K.K. Hof- und Staatsdruckerei) (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Welt-Ausstellung 1873 in Wien. Catalog der Ersten Temporären Thier-Ausstellung. Vom 31. Mai bis 9. Juni. (Wien: "Die Presse") (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Kerpely, Anton. Das Eisen auf der Wiener Weltausstellung 1873... (Schemnitz, Czech: August Joerges) (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Lucas, Félix. Étude historique et statistique sur les voies de communication de la France... (Paris: Imprimerie Nationale), 1873. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Keleti, Karl. Skizze der Landeskunde Ungarns. Einleitender Theil des ung. Kataloges. Zur Wiener Weltausstellung... (Budapest: Athenaeum), [1873]. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Beilstein, F. Die Chemische Grossindustrie auf der Weltausstellung zu Wien (Leipzig: Quandt & Händel), 1873. (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Wiener Weltausstellung. Amtlicher Katalog der Austellung des Deutschen Reiches... (Berlin: R. v. Decker), 1873. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Notice sur l'empire du Japon et sur sa participation à l'exposition universelle de Vienne, 1873...(Yokohama: C. Lévy) (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Norwegischer Special-Katalog der Weltausstellung 1873 in Wien. (Christiania: J. Chr. Gundersen) (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Blake, W.P. and Pettit, Henry. Reports of the Vienna Universal Exhibition, 1873 Made to the U.S. Centennial Commission. (Philadelphia: McLaughlin Brothers), 1873 July (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Commonwealth of Massachusetts. Report of the Commissioners to the Exposition at Vienna... (Boston: Wright & Potter), 1874 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Pettit, Henry. Final Report to the U.S. Centennial Commission on the Structures Erected for the Vienna Universal Exhibition, 1873 and Previous Exhibitions in London and Paris (Philadelphia: McLaughlin Brothers), 1873 September (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - [Vienna Universal Exhibition. Report of W.P. Blake.] Supplemental Report., [1873] (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Vienna Universal Exhibition - 1873. General Regulations for the Foreign Exhibitors and Commissions. (Washington, D.C.: Government Printing Office), 1872. (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Biographisches Lexikon (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Band 1. Heft 1, 2. Wien, [1873] (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Band 1. Heft 3. Wien, [1873] (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Vienna scandal (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - Analysis of the Evidence and Reports on the Vienna Scandal... (Hackensack, N.J.: Republican Steam Book and Job Print), 1874. (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - A Statement of the Proceedings...in Relation to the Suspension and Removal of Gen'l. Thomas B. Van Buren, from the Office of Commissioner General from the United States to the Universal Exposition, at Vienna, Austria. (Hackensack, N.J.: New Jersey Republican Steam Presses), 1873. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Paris. Exposition universelle, 1878
    - Exposition universelle de 1878. Guide-itinèraire du visiteur... (Paris: E. Dentu), [ca. 1878]. (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Exposition de l'administration des forêts. 3e section. Les produits forestiers. Leur emploi dans les constructions et dans l'industrie. Notice sur l'emploi du bois dans la fabrication du papier. (Paris: Imprimerie Nationale), 1877. (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Ministère de l'agriculture et du commerce. Administration des forêts. (Paris Imprimerie nationale), 1878
      - Barré, H. et Roussel, L. Notice sur les procédés de lever des plans et sur leur application au cadastre et aux autres services publics (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - Brenot, M.L. Remarques sur deux variétés d'épicéa (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - Croizette-Desnoyers, M. Notice sur le gemmage du pin maritime (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - Croisette-Desnoyers, M. Notice sur les divers emplois du hêtre (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - De Kirwan, M. Notice sur l'industrie des écorces à tan (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - De Montrichard, M. Notice sur la règ1e à eubage des arbres (Box 12, Folder 18)
      - Demontzey, P. Notice. sur les cartes, dessins, modèles et ouvrages relatifs aux travaux du service du reboisement des montagnes dans le Bassin de la Durance (Box 12, Folder 18)
      - Fautrat, M. Observations météorologiques faites de 1877 a 1878 (Box 12, Folder 19)
      - Gallot, M. Notice sur le débit et les emplois du sapin, de l'épicéa et du méléze (Box 12, Folder 19)
      - George-Grimblot, A. Études sur la truffe (Box 12, Folder 19)
      - Grosjean, M. Notice sur l'industrie du sabotage dans le département de la Lozère (Box 12, Folder 20)
      - Levret, M.H. Note sur deux nouveaux procédés ayant pour effect d'activer le développement des racines latérales du chêne dans la culture en pépinière (Box 12, Folder 20)
      - [Matthieu, A.] Météorologie comparée agricole et forestière (Box 12, Folder 20)
      - Rapport de la commission instituée pour l'expérimentation du procédé d'écorçage des bois par lachaleur dit de de nomaison (Box 12, Folder 20)
      - Reboisement et gazonnement des montagnes. Monographies de travaux exécutés dans les Alpes, les Cévennes et les Pyrénées., 1861-1878. (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Paris. Exposition universelle, 1900
    - Ministère du commerce, de l'industrie des postes et des télégraphes. Exposition universelle internationale de 1900 à Paris. Rapports du jury international. (Paris: Imprimerie Nationale), 1902
      - Mourier, Charles. Classe 112. Assistance publique et Bienfaisance privée. Institutions pénitentiaires (Box 13, Folder 22)
      - Groupe XVI. Économie sociale. - Hygiène Assistance publique. (Box 14, Folder 23)
        - Premiere partie. - Classes 101 à 103 (Box 14, Folder 23)
        - Deuxième partie. - Classes 104 à 108 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - The International Universal Exhibition of 1900. Chronicles of the World's Great Products. Volume Annexe. Official Catalogue United States Exhibitors. (Paris: Lemercier), [ca. 1900]. (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - St. Louis. Louisiana Purchase Exposition, 1904
    - World's Fair Bulletin (St. Louis: World's Fair Publishing Co.)
      - Vol. 2, No. 10, (1901 Aug) (Box 14, Folder 26)
      - Vol. 3, Nos. 2-5, (1901 December - 1902 Mar) (Box 14, Folder 27)
      - Vol. 3, Nos. 7-9, (1902 November - 1903 Apr) (Box 14, Folder 28)
      - Vol. 4, Nos. 1-6, (1902 November - 1903 Apr) (Box 15, Folder 29)
      - Vol. 4, Nos. 8, 11, 12, (1903 Jun, Sep, Oct) (Box 15, Folder 30)
      - Vol. 5, Nos. 1, 2, 4, 6, (1903 Nov, Dec, 1904 Feb, Apr) (Box 15, Folder 31)
      - Vol. 5, Nos. 7-10, (1904 May - Aug) (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Toluca, México. Segunda Exposición Industrial del Estado de México, 1902
    - Memoria de la Segunda Exposición Nacional Permanente. Presentada por el Secretario de la Junta Directiva C. Coronel José María Cardeñas Madero. Edición Oficial. ([Toluca]: Oficina Tipográfica), 1902. (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Philadelphia. Centennial Exhibition, 1876
    - The National Celebration of the Centennial Anniversary of the Independence of the United States by an International Universal Exhibition, to Be Held in Philadephia in the Year 1876. Report to the Congress by the United States Centennial Commission, February, 1873... (Washington, D.C.: Government Printing Office) (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - China. Catalogue of the Chinese Imperial Maritime Customs Collection, at the United States International Exhibition, Philadelphia, 1876. Published by Order of the Inspector General of Chinese Maritime Customs. (Shanghai: Statistical Department of the Inspectorate General of Customs) (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - United States International Centennial Exhibition of 1876. Catalogue of the Articles and Objects Exhibited by the United States Navy Department by the United States Government Building, Fairmount Park, Philadelphia, P. (Philadelphia: J.B. Lippincott & Co.) (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - Illustrated catalogues
      - Centennial Portfolio. 2nd Series. Eight Views of Centennial Buildings... and Map of Centennial Grounds. (Philadelphia: Thos. Hunter), [ca. 1876]. (Box 16, Folder 37)
      - The Illustrated Catalogue of the Centennial Exhibition, Philadelphia, 1876. Illustrated by George C. Bell and Other Eminent Artists. (Philadelphia: John Filmer)
        - Parts 1-4 (Box 16, Folder 38)
        - Parts 5-8 (Box 16, Folder 39)
        - Parts 9, 10, 18 (Box 16, Folder 40)
  - Chicago. World's Columbian Exposition, 1893
    - Department of Publicity and Promotion, Jackson Park, Chicago, Ill. Chicago and World's Columbian Exposition. Chicago: Midway Publishing Co., 1893 (Box 16, Folder 41)
  - New Orleans. World's Industrial and Cotton Centennial Exposition, 1884-1885
    - Map of New Orleans and View of the Exposition Buildings, Ca. 1884 (Box 16, Folder 42)
  - Buffalo. Pan-American Exposition, 1901
    - The Pan-American Exposition. Buffalo, N.Y., U.S.A. From May 1 to November 1, 1901., Ca. 1901 (Box 16, Folder 43)
  - Chicago. Century of Progress International Exposition, 1933
    - Souvenir of Prof. W. Heckler's Trained Flea Circus. A Century of Progress Exhibition. Chicago, 1933 (Box 16, Folder 44)
  - San Francisco. Panama-Pacific International Exposition, 1915
    - Advertisements., Ca. 1915 (Box 16, Folder 45)
  - St. Louis. Louisiana Purchase Exposition, 1904
    - Connecticut at the World's Fair. Report of the Commissioners from Connecticut to the Louisiana Purchase Exposition Held at St. Louis, 1904. Hartford: Case Lockwood & Brainard Co., 1906 (Box 16, Folder 46)
    - Thompson, Thomas P. Louisiana Writers, Native and Resident, Including Others Whose Books Belong to a Bibliography of That State,...Compiled for Louisiana State Commision Louisiana Purchase Exposition. New Orleans, 1904 (Box 16, Folder 47)
  - Philadelphia. Centennial Exhibition, 1876
    - Memorial of the International Exhibition at Philadelphia. Philadelphia: Thos. Hunter, 1876 (Box 16, Folder 48)
    - Gems of the Centennial Exhibition: Consisting of Illustrated Descriptions of Objects of an Artistic Character,...at the Philadelphia International Exhibition of 1876. New York: D. Appleton & Co., 1977 (Box 17, Folder 49)
  - Chicago. World's Columbian Exposition, 1893
    - The Javanese theatre, Java village, Midway Plaisance, containing also a short description of Java, the people, languages, customs, food, products, etc. Chicago, Java Chicago Exhibition Syndicate, 1893. unpaged. illus. (Box 17, Folder 50)
- OVERSIZE
  - Chicago. World's Columbian Exposition, 1893
    - Blank engraved printing surface [prepared by the U.S. Treasury Department; authorizing the World's Columbian Exposition to decree a medal for specific merit....] (Box 18)